{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Integrative Programming",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "Data Types",
    "LastModified": "17 May 2024",
    "Authors": [
      ""
    ],
    "References": [
      "Any external links/handouts should be referenced here"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "This is a name of a program component that is used to identify namespaces, classes, methods, etc. and is defined by the user.",
      "answer": "Identifier",
      "choices": [
        "Identifier",
        "Keyword",
        "Variable name",
        "Data value"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following syntax rules in naming an identifier is FALSE ?",
      "answer": "The classes and methods in C# can begin with either an uppercase or lowercase letter.",
      "choices": [
        "The classes and methods in C# can begin with either an uppercase or lowercase letter.",
        "It must start with a letter of the English alphabet or an underscore character.",
        "White spaces in the names are not allowed.",
        "Identifier names are case sensitive."
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Based on the syntax rules of C#, which of the identifiers are NOT VALID?",
      "answer": "1score",
      "choices": [
        "1score",
        "_score",
        "grade1",
        "firstName"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are words that a programming language use that possess a special predefined meaning and purpose to the compiler. The use of these words are not allowed and would cause a syntax error.",
      "answer": "Keywords / Reserved words",
      "choices": [
        "Keywords / Reserved words",
        "Identifiers",
        "Variable names",
        "Programming terms"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following words are not part of C#'s keywords?",
      "answer": "operate",
      "choices": [
        "operate",
        "abstract",
        "public",
        "return"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is an identifier and a memory location that stores a specific value.",
      "answer": "Variable",
      "choices": [
        "Variable",
        "Constant",
        "String",
        "Integer"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following accurately depicts this description: A variable of data type integer named age with a value of 45.",
      "answer": "int age = 45;",
      "choices": [
        "int age = 45;",
        "integer age = 45;",
        "age = (int) 45;",
        "age = 45 (int);"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "When creating a program, the variable name must be meaningful and easy to understand its value.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following follows the Camel Case notation?",
      "answer": "totalPrice",
      "choices": [
        "totalPrice",
        "TotalPrice",
        "Total_Price",
        "Totalprice"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is an identifier and a memory location whose value can't be changed during program execution.",
      "answer": "Constant",
      "choices": [
        "Variable",
        "Constant",
        "String",
        "Integer"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Constants can have no value at the time of declaration.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following accurately depicts this description: <br> A constant of data type double named EARTHGRAVITY with a value of 9.8",
      "answer": "const double EARTHGRAVITY = 9.8;",
      "choices": [
        "const double EARTHGRAVITY = 9.8;",
        "constant double EARTHGRAVITY = 9.8;",
        "gravity = 9.8;",
        "Const double EARTHGRAVITY = 9.8;"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The names of constants must be in all lowercase letters to make it easily identifiable.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "These are used to specify a set of values and their operations associated with variables or constants.",
      "answer": "Data Types",
      "choices": [
        "Data Types",
        "Data Values",
        "Data Set",
        "Data Operations"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This C# type of primitive data types store the value directly.",
      "answer": "Value Types",
      "choices": [
        "Value Types",
        "Direct Types",
        "Reference Types",
        "Straight Types"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This C# type of primitive data types don't store the actual value in a variable or constant but instead store the reference where the value is actually stored.",
      "answer": "Reference Types",
      "choices": [
        "Value Types",
        "Direct Types",
        "Reference Types",
        "Straight Types"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The int data type is a value type.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The class objects, strings, and arrays are reference types.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "A data type is a value type if it holds the data within its own memory allocation.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "A data type is a reference type if it stores the address where the value is stored, meaning that the reference types contain the memory lcoation of where the value is stored.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is the process of converting a value of 1 type of data to another data type, ensuring that a function correctly process the variables.",
      "answer": "Type Conversion / Casting",
      "choices": [
        "Type Conversion / Casting",
        "Value Conversion / Casting",
        "Value Transformation",
        "Type Convertion / Casting"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is the conversion of a lower precision data type to a value of higher precision type.",
      "answer": "Implicit Conversion / Casting",
      "choices": [
        "Implicit Conversion / Casting",
        "Explicit Conversion / Casting",
        "Type Conversionv / Casting",
        "Convert To Short"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is the conversion allows the the user to convert a value of higher precision into a lower precision data type usig a cast operator.",
      "answer": "Explicit Conversion / Casting",
      "choices": [
        "Implicit Conversion / Casting",
        "Explicit Conversion / Casting",
        "Type Conversionv / Casting",
        "Convert To Short"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "A compiler doesn't automatically perform an implicit conversion if the precision of the data type is lower tha the precision of the preferred data type.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following accurately depicts this description: <br> Convert the value 25 of the byte variable named a into an integer data type named b.",
      "answer": "byte a = 25; <br> int b = a;",
      "choices": [
        "byte a = 25; <br> int b = a;",
        "byte a = 25; <br> int b = 25;",
        "int b = (int) a;",
        "byte a = 25; <b> int a = 25;"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "There is no implicit conversion of any data type to char type.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The bool and double data types have no possible implicit conversion to other data types.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Explicit conversion involves the risk of losing information.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following accurately depicts this description: <br> The variable of data type double named price has a value of 75.5 which is then set as the value for the integer variable named varA.",
      "answer": "double price = 75.5; <br> int varA = (int) price;",
      "choices": [
        "double price = 75.5; <br> int varA = (int) price;",
        "double price = 75.5; <br> int varA = price;",
        "double price = 75.5; <br> int varA = toInt price;",
        "double price = 75.5; <br> int varA = 75.5;"
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    },
    {
      "question": "The explicit conversion of a data type to char will retrn the corresponding character of the value from the ASCII table.",
      "answer": "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
      "choices": [
        "THE STATEMENT IS TRUE ",
        "THE STATEMENT IS FALSE "
      ],
      "reference": "02 Handout 1",
      "term": "Prelim"
    }
  ]
}
